### Contact



+1 226-606-6590



orusaishtiaq@gmail.com



linkedin.com/orusa-akhtar



github.com/orusaish



orusaish.github.io

## **Technical Skills**

JavaScript

**HTML** 

**CSS** 

Python

Bash

C#

C/C++

### **Frameworks**

Node.js

MongoDB

MySQL

**Express** 

HandleBars

Sequelize

React

**Firebase** 

Axios

**JQuery** 

Git

# **Orusa Akhtar**

# Summary

A full stack web developer with a passion for front end web development and back end development. Enjoy working in a team and collaborate to create meaningful web applications. Certified in full stack web development from the University of Toronto and hold master's in computer applications. Experience in web development using the MERN stack and latest industry standards.

# **Projects**

### **ParkEZ**



- A web app that helps truckers and truck companies reserve and view parking spaces
- Built using React, Nodejs, Express, JavaScript, Sequelize, Passport, axios, bootstrap and MySQL

### Train Scheduler





- A web app to display train arrival and departure information
- Built using moment.js, HTML, CSS and JavaScript

#### Bamazon





- An Amazon like storefront that helps maintain inventory and customer support
- Built using MySQL and Nodejs

# **Experience**

## Freelancing Web Development

Jan 2019 - Present

Designing and developing web pages

Home Tutor 2006-2011

Tutored Math for middle and high school students

#### Math and Science Teacher

2004-2006

Taught math and science to grade 9 and 10 students in the International Indian School, Jeddah

## Assistant Computer Science Professor

2002-2004

Sri Sathya Sai Arts and Science college, Bhopal India

- Taught data structures and database management systems
- Assisted students in programming assignments and debugging issues

# **Education**

# Full stack web development

University of Toronto, Mississauga

# Master of Computer Application (MCA)

Samrat Ashok Technological Institute, Vidisha, India

### Bachelor of Science (BSc)

Barkatullah University, Bhopal India